# Hi, I'm Jose Martinez Castro

I am an industrial designer and mechanical engineer passionate about using biodesign and novel technologies to create a sustainable future. I have professional experience in design and research for biomedical and sports application. On the side, I enjoy rock climbing, swimming, and 3D animation.

# Skills

- · Blender 3D/SolidWorks/Keyshot
- · Adobe Creative Suite
- · 3D Printing
- · Arduino Prototyping
- · Matlab Data Analysis
- · C/C++ Programming

# Education

2019 - 2021

### Technische Universiteit Delft

Master of Science Integrated Product Design

2014 - 2019

# **University of British Columbia**

Bachelor of Applied Science Mech. Engineering - Biomedical

#### Awards

2019 & 2020

TU Delft Merit Scholarship (€5.000)

2018

Geyer Family Award in Biomedical Engineering (\$2.800)

2018 & 2016

NSERC USRA Award (\$9.000)

2016

UBC Trek Excellence Scholarship (\$1.500)

2016

UBC Frank Vernon Memorial Scholarship (\$500)

# Contact

+31 626720481

jfmartinez18@hotmail.com

Nieuwe Langendijk 4, 2611VK Delft, ZH, Nederland

# Experience

# **Technische Universiteit Delft**

Oct 2021 - Present

Junior Researcher - Materials Experience Lab

- Developing a digital biodesign tool to simulate the growing conditions of Flavo bacteria in an interactive 3D environment using procedural material textures in Blender 3D.
- · Writing academic paper for DIS conference on interactive textiles.

### **Technische Universiteit Delft**

Oct 2020 - Jul 2021

Teaching Assistant - Industrial Design

- **ID5413-19 Material Driven Design** assisting professor in the coordination of day to day activities of a project based course.
- **ID4135-16 Modelling** assisting students with Matlab programming and engineering analysis of products through online Q&A sessions.
- **People in Transit Minor** providing live demos and assisting students in automotive 3D modelling and rendering/animation using Blender.

### **Arbutus Medical**

Jan 2018 - Aug 2018

R&D Engineering Intern

- Developed the manufacturing process of the new product through intuitive jig design and clear visual instructions.
- Designed automated testing jigs to validate durability of the product involving maching, electronics, and programming.
- Involved in designing product accessory through rapid prototyping and validating usability with doctors and engineers.

# **UBC Aerodynamics Laboratory**

Jun 2017 - Sep 2017

Research Intern

- Performed wind tunnel textile aerodynamics experiments and analysis for Nike, Sugoi, Garneau, and the Canadian Olympic team.
- Developed an automated wind speed control system for UBC's largest wind tunnel using a PID controller with Matlab and Labview.

# **Evasc Medical Systems**

Sep 2016 - Dec 2016

Engineering Intern

- Designed inspection jigs for use within a sterile environment with the use of milling and lathe machines.
- Performed laboratory and manufacturing processes within a clean room environment to assemble the sterile product.